Guide to the Evelyn Rich Papers, 1956-1993 RL.11363
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Evelyn Rich papers
1954-1993
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Rich, Evelyn Beatrice Mackenzie, 1957-
RL.11363
5.0 Linear Feet
Collection consists of audio cassette tapes, transcripts, notes, photographs, and collected printed materials from Evelyn Rich's doctoral research on Ku Klux Klan ideology, conducted between 1984 and 1986. Contains interviews with Klan leaders and white supremacists David Duke, Don Black, Glen Miller, Stanley McCollum, and others, as well as recordings of rallies and speeches. Also includes documentation of Klan activities and copies of literature published by Invisible Empire, Knights of the KKK; the White Patriot Party; Knights of the KKK; the Populist Party; Mountain Church; NAAWP; Institute for Historical Review; and other white supremacists and white Christian nationalist groups.
Arrangement
Arranged into series: Interviews; Correspondence and Name Files; and Far Right Groups: Notes, Printed Material, and Ephemera.
Biographical / Historical
Evelyn Rich (1957- ) was born in England, and arrived in the United States in 1978. She travelled extensively through the country researching her dissertation between 1983 and 1986; during that period she met and interviewed many Ku Klux Klan members and other white nationalists. Rich earned her doctorate from Boston University in 1988. She is also the partner of Jared Taylor, founder of American Renaissance (another white nationalist group, based in Northern Virginia).
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research. Original audiovisual materials are closed to use. Contact Research Services to request the production of listening copies.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Evelyn Rich Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a purchase in 2016.
Acquired through support of Stan Brown, Trinity '92.
Collection Overview
This collection consists of audio cassettes, transcripts, photographs, notes, and printed materials collected and created by Evelyn Rich as she researched her dissertation, "Ku Klux Klan Ideology: 1954-1988." Rich travelled the United States between 1983 and 1986, attending Ku Klux Klan rallies, meeting white nationalists like David Duke, Louis Beam, Roger Handley, Don Black, and Glen Miller. This collection contains her interviews with these men, as well as lower-level Klansmen and Klan women, discussing their backgrounds, political and racial beliefs, and their feelings and opinions on issues such as integration, the Republican Party, the Populist Party, and states' rights. The collection also includes recordings and photographs of Klan rallies, as well as copies of various white supremacist and white Christian nationalist literature and newspapers, including The Klansmen, Fiery Cross, NAAWP News, and The White Patriot.
A portion of the collection documents Rich's relationship with David Duke and Don Black, two prominent Klan leaders in the mid-1980s. Her relationship with Black is recorded through correspondence and several interviews, as well as photographs and notes from a roadtrip the two took together in 1986. Materials from Duke include extensive interviews about his beliefs on issues such as integration, the Holocaust, genetics, and white supremacy; poetry by Duke written for Rich and photographs from their trips and time together; newsletters, speeches, and political campaign ephemera from Duke's run for U.S. Senate, Louisiana governorship, and the presidency; and newspaper clippings quoting the Rich audio tapes (now held in this collection, then housed at Tulane University), which record Duke's racist and anti-Semitic ideology.
Related Materials
See also: Southern Poverty Law Center Intelligence Project Collection, also held in the Rubenstein Library.
White supremacy movements -- United States; Hate Speech -- United States; Holocaust denial literature -- United States.; Whites -- Southern States -- Politics and government -- 20th century; Whites -- Race identity -- United States; Ku Klux Klan (1915- ); Institute for Historical Review; Duke, David Ernest; Populist Party (U.S.: 1984-1996); Beam, Louis R.; Invisible Empire, Knights of the Ku Klux Klan (1975); Knights of the Ku Klux Klan (1975); National Association for the Advancement of White People; Mountain Church of Jesus Christ the Savior (Cohoctah, Mich.); White Patriot Party; Miller, Glenn, 1940-; Ellis, C. P. (Claiborne Paul)
- Interviews, 1984-1987
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically
  Scope and Contents
  For some interviews only transcripts were kept. For others, multiple audiocassette copies were made; however, for ease of use, this collection guide lists only the tapes believed to be the originals, as well as the digital files created at the Rubenstein Library from those tapes. For a full list of audiocassettes in the collection, contact Rubenstein Library Research Services.
  - Clay Ballwin with Joe Grady, Yadkin County, NC, 1984-08-04; 11 pages
    Ballwin: Grand Dragon, North Carolina White Knights of Liberty, Knight of the Ku Klux Klan; Grady: Imperial Wizard, Knight of the Ku Klux Klan
    - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Transcript pdf (Digital-materials RL11363-SET-0002, Object RL11363-PDF-0001.PDF)
  - A.J. Barker, Yadkin County, NC, 1984-08-04; 6 pages
    Vice Chairman, NC Populist Party
    - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Transcript pdf (Digital-materials RL11363-SET-0002, Object RL11363-PDF-0002.PDF)
  - Louis Beam, Licking, MO, 1984-06-24; 5 pages
    Texas Grand Dragon of the Knights of the Ku Klux Klan, leader Aryan Nations.
    - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Transcript pdf (Digital-materials RL11363-SET-0002, Object RL11363-PDF-0003.PDF)
  - Hal Beck, Cary, NC, 1984-07-25; 17 pages
    Chairman, NC Populist Party
    - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Transcript pdf (Digital-materials RL11363-SET-0002, Object RL11363-PDF-0004.PDF)
  - Don Black with Dr. Buford B. Sanders, Homewood, AL, 1985-03-12; 01:55:55
    Black: National Director, Knights of the Ku Klux Klan; Sanders: physician, future member Conservative Citizens Council Assocation; location: Bennigan's Restaurant, Homewood, AL
    - Original audiocassette, sides 1 and 2 (Box 3, Audio-cassette RL11363-CS-0009)
    - Original audiocassette, side 1 (Box 3, Audio-cassette RL11363-CS-0015)
    - Digital audio file, part 1 (Digital-materials RL11363-SET-0001, Object RL11363-CS-0009_01.WAV)
    - Digital audio file, part 2 (Digital-materials RL11363-SET-0001, Object RL11363-CS-0009_02.WAV)
    - Digital audio file, part 3 (Digital-materials RL11363-SET-0001, Object RL11363-CS-0015_01.WAV)
    - Transcript, 35 pages (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Transcript pdf (Digital-materials RL11363-SET-0002, Object RL11363-PDF-0005.PDF)
  - Don Black, Birmingham, AL, 1985-03-24; 01:33:12
    National Director, Knights of the Ku Klux Klan
    - Original audiocassette, sides 1 and 2 (Box 3, Audio-cassette RL11363-CS-0005)
    - Digital audio file, part 1 (Digital-materials RL11363-SET-0001, Object RL11363-CS-0005_01.WAV)
    - Digital audio file, part 2 (Digital-materials RL11363-SET-0001, Object RL11363-CS-0005_02.WAV)
    - Transcript, 25 pages (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Transcript pdf (Digital-materials RL11363-SET-0002, Object RL11363-PDF-0006.PDF)
  - Jim Blair, Fredonia, Alabama, 1985-07-23; 01:24:09
    Imperial Wizard, Invisible Empire, Knights of the Ku Klux Klan
    - Original audiocassette, sides 1 and 2 (Box 4, Audio-cassette RL11363-CS-0041)
    - Digital audio file, part 1 (Digital-materials RL11363-SET-0001, Object RL11363-CS-0041_01.WAV)
    - Digital audio file, part 2 (Digital-materials RL11363-SET-0001, Object RL11363-CS-0041_02.WAV)
  - Bobby Bradshaw, Rutherford County, NC, 1984-08-05; 5 pages
    North Carolina Grand Kludd, Invisible Empire, Knights of the Ku Klux Klan
    - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Transcript pdf (Digital-materials RL11363-SET-0002, Object RL11363-PDF-0008.PDF)
  - Reverend J.M. Drummond, Huntsville, AL, 1984-07-01; 21 pages
    Oldest living Ku Klux Klan member.
    - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Transcript pdf (Digital-materials RL11363-SET-0002, Object RL11363-PDF-0009.PDF)
  - David Duke, Metairie, LA, interview 1, 1985-03-18; 02:55:57
    - Original audiocassette, side 1 (Box 3, Audio-cassette RL11363-CS-0016)
    - Original audiocassette, sides 1 and 2 (Box 3, Audio-cassette RL11363-CS-0017)
    - Original audiocassette, side 2 (Box 3, Audio-cassette RL11363-CS-0011)
    - Digital audio file, part 1 (Digital-materials RL11363-SET-0001, Object RL11363-CS-0016_01.WAV)
    - Digital audio file, part 2 (Digital-materials RL11363-SET-0001, Object RL11363-CS-0017_01.WAV)
    - Digital audio file, part 3 (Digital-materials RL11363-SET-0001, Object RL11363-CS-0017_02.WAV)
    - Digital audio file, part 4 (Digital-materials RL11363-SET-0001, Object RL11363-CS-0011_02.WAV)
    - Transcript, 53 pages (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Transcript pdf (Digital-materials RL11363-SET-0002, Object RL11363-PDF-0010.PDF)
  - David Duke, Metairie, LA, interview 2, 1985-03-20; 32:34
    Partial audio. See transcript for full interview.
    - Original audiocassette, side 1 (Box 3, Audio-cassette RL11363-CS-0011)
    - Original audiocassette, side 1 (Box 2, Audio-cassette RL11363-CS-0042)
    - Digital audio file (Digital-materials RL11363-SET-0001, Object RL11363-CS-0011_01.WAV)
    - Digital audio file (beginning through 00:14:46) (Digital-materials RL11363-SET-0001, Object RL11363-CS-0042.WAV)
    - Transcript, 21 pages (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Transcript pdf (Digital-materials RL11363-SET-0002, Object RL11363-PDF-0011.PDF)
  - David Duke, excerpts, 1985-03
    Incomplete excerpts of transcripts annotated: Genetic Potential, Political Ambition, Holocaust
    - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - David Duke and Joe Fields, Culver City, CA, 1986-02-17; 00:40:54
    - Original audiocassette, side 1 (Box 3, Audio-cassette RL11363-CS-0001)
    - Digital audio file (Digital-materials RL11363-SET-0001, Object RL11363-CS-0001.WAV)
    - Transcript, 18 pages (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Transcript pdf (Digital-materials RL11363-SET-0002, Object RL11363-PDF-0015.PDF)
    - Annotated excerpts produced by Lousiana Coalition Against Racism and Nazism (1991), original audiocassette, sides 1 and 2, 00:51:52 (Box 3, Audio-cassette RL11363-CS-0004)
    - Annotated excerpts produced by Lousiana Coalition Against Racism and Nazism (1991), digital audio file, part 1 (Digital-materials RL11363-SET-0001, Object RL11363-CS-0004_01.WAV)
    - Annotated excerpts produced by Lousiana Coalition Against Racism and Nazism (1991), digital audio file, part 2 (Digital-materials RL11363-SET-0001, Object RL11363-CS-0004_02.WAV)
  - John Edwards, Rutherford County, NC, 1984-08-05; 7 pages
    Eastern Grand Dragon, Invisible Empire, Knights of the KKK.
    - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Transcript pdf (Digital-materials RL11363-SET-0002, Object RL11363-PDF-0013.PDF)
  - C.P. Ellis, Atlanta, GA, 1985-08-02; 00:51:59
    Former Exalted Cyclops, Durham NC Chapter of U.K.A.
    - Original audiocassette, sides 1 and 2 (Box 3, Audio-cassette RL11363-CS-0020)
    - Digital audio file, part 1 (Digital-materials RL11363-SET-0001, Object RL11363-CS-0020_01.WAV)
    - Digital audio file, part 2 (Digital-materials RL11363-SET-0001, Object RL11363-CS-0020_02.WAV)
  - Ed Fields, Atlanta, GA, 01:26:27
    Vice-Chairman, National States Rights Party; founder of The New Order of Knights of the KKK.
    - Original audiocassette, side 1 (Box 3, Audio-cassette RL11363-CS-0031)
    - Original audiocassette (Box 3, Audio-cassette RL11363-CS-0007)
    - Digital audio file, part 1 (Digital-materials RL11363-SET-0001, Object RL11363-CS-0031_01.WAV)
    - Digital audio file, part 2 (Digital-materials RL11363-SET-0001, Object RL11363-CS-0007.WAV)
    - Transcript, 20 pages (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Transcript pdf (Digital-materials RL11363-SET-0002, Object RL11363-PDF-0014.PDF)
  - Joe Grady, Winston-Salem, NC, 1984-07-30; 19 pages
    Imperial Wizard, White Knights of Liberty of the KKK.
    - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Transcript pdf (Digital-materials RL11363-SET-0002, Object RL11363-PDF-0016.PDF)
  - Martha Green, Rutherford County, NC, 1984-08-05; 7 pages
    Rutherford County Guard, Invisible Empire of the KKK.
    - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Transcript pdf (Digital-materials RL11363-SET-0002, Object RL11363-PDF-0017.PDF)
  - Virgil Griffin, Mt. Holly, NC, 1984-07-26; 14 pages
    - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Transcript pdf (Digital-materials RL11363-SET-0002, Object RL11363-PDF-0018.PDF)
  - Roger Handley, Homewood, AL, 1985-07-29; 01:31:56
    Grand Dragon, Alabama White Knights of the KKK
    - Original audiocassette, sides 1 and 2 (Box 3, Audio-cassette RL11363-CS-0028)
    - Original audiocassette, side 1 (Box 3, Audio-cassette RL11363-CS-0029)
    - Digital audio file, part 1 (Digital-materials RL11363-SET-0001, Object RL11363-CS-0028_01.WAV)
    - Digital audio file, part 2 (Digital-materials RL11363-SET-0001, Object RL11363-CS-0028_02.WAV)
    - Digital audio file, part 3 (Digital-materials RL11363-SET-0001, Object RL11363-CS-0029_01.WAV)
  - Grady Hoppes, Rutherford County, NC, 1984-08-05; 6 pages
    Rutherford County Titan, Captain of the Security Guard, Invisible Empire, Knights of the KKK.
    - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Transcript pdf (Digital-materials RL11363-SET-0002, Object RL11363-PDF-0019.PDF)
  - Jim Bob (no last name given), Rutherford County, NC, 1984-08-05; 7 pages
    Cleveland County Great Titan, Invisible Empire, Knights of the KKK.
    - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Transcript pdf (Digital-materials RL11363-SET-0002, Object RL11363-PDF-0007.PDF)
  - Ron Johnson, Springfield, VA, 1985-07-08; 00:46:12
    National Alliance and NAAWP member.
    - Original audiocassette, sides 1 and 2 (Box 4, Audio-cassette RL11363-CS-0036)
    - Digital audio file, part 1 (Digital-materials RL11363-SET-0001, Object RL11363-CS-0036.WAV)
  - Van D. Loman with Don Black and Gary Nungester, Cincinnati, OH, 1986-04-21; 01:21:39
    Former Imperial Klaliff of the Invisible Empire; Ohio State Chairman of the Populist Party.
    - Original audiocassette, sides 1 and 2 (Box 3, Audio-cassette RL11363-CS-0008)
    - Original audiocassette, side 1 (Box 3, Audio-cassette RL11363-CS-0023)
    - Digital audio file, part 1 (Digital-materials RL11363-SET-0001, Object RL11363-CS-0008_01.WAV)
    - Digital audio file, part 2 (Digital-materials RL11363-SET-0001, Object RL11363-CS-0008_02.WAV)
    - Digital audio file, part 3 (Digital-materials RL11363-SET-0001, Object RL11363-CS-0023.WAV)
    - Transcript, 18 pages (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Transcript pdf (Digital-materials RL11363-SET-0002, Object RL11363-PDF-0020.PDF)
  - B.M. (no name given), Ellenboro, NC, 1984-08-05; 7 pages
    Captain of the Guards and Titan, Cleveland County Chapter of the Invisible Empire, Knights of the KKK.
    - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Transcript pdf (Digital-materials RL11363-SET-0002, Object RL11363-PDF-0021.PDF)
  - Stanley McCollum, Tuscumbia, AL, 1984-07-20; 19 pages
    Imperial Wizard, Knights of the KKK.
    - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Transcript pdf (Digital-materials RL11363-SET-0002, Object RL11363-PDF-0022.PDF)
  - Stanley McCollum, Fullerton, AL, 1985-07-28; 01:18:55
    - Original audiocassette, sides 1 and 2 (Box 3, Audio-cassette RL11363-CS-0030)
    - Digital audio file, part 1 (Digital-materials RL11363-SET-0001, Object RL11363-CS-0030_01.WAV)
    - Digital audio file, part 2 (Digital-materials RL11363-SET-0001, Object RL11363-CS-0030_02.WAV)
  - Tom Metzger with David Duke, Los Angeles, CA, 01:16:03
    - Original audiocassette, sides 1 and 2, 1986-02-16 (Box 4, Audio-cassette RL11363-CS-0037)
    - Digital audio file, part 1 (Digital-materials RL11363-SET-0001, Object RL11363-CS-0037_01.WAV)
    - Digital audio file, part 2 (Digital-materials RL11363-SET-0001, Object RL11363-CS-0037_02.WAV)
    - Transcript, 18 pages (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Transcript pdf (Digital-materials RL11363-SET-0002, Object RL11363-PDF-0023.PDF)
  - Glenn Miller, Angier, NC, 1985-07-11; 00:47:15
    Head of White Patriot Party. Also known as Frazier Glenn Miller, Jr. or Frazier Glenn Cross.
    - Original audiocassette, sides 1 and 2 (Box 3, Audio-cassette RL11363-CS-0006)
    - Digital audio file, part 1 (Digital-materials RL11363-SET-0001, Object RL11363-CS-0006_01.WAV)
    - Digital audio file, part 2 (Digital-materials RL11363-SET-0001, Object RL11363-CS-0006_02.WAV)
    - Transcript, 14 pages (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Transcript pdf (Digital-materials RL11363-SET-0002, Object RL11363-PDF-0024.PDF)
  - Martha "Marty" Nathan, 1985; 00:23:02
    Widow of Mike Nathan, murdered in the Greensboro Massacre in 1979 (see interview with Glenn Miller).
    - Original audiocassette, side 2 (Box 3, Audio-cassette RL11363-CS-0032)
    - Digital audio file (Digital-materials RL11363-SET-0001, Object RL11363-CS-0032_02.WAV)
  - Bill Robinson, Falkville, AL, 1984-07-01; 14 pages
    Alabama White Knights of the KKK; candidate for mayor of Falkville, AL.
    - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Transcript pdf (Digital-materials RL11363-SET-0002, Object RL11363-PDF-0025.PDF)
  - Robert Scoggins, Rutherford County, NC, 1984-08-05; 11 pages
    Emperor, Invisible Empire, South Carolina Knights of the KKK.
    - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Transcript pdf (Digital-materials RL11363-SET-0002, Object RL11363-PDF-0026.PDF)
  - Jerry Sutes with Joe Grady, Yadkin County, NC, 1984-08-04; 10 pages
    Sutes: Titan of the 9th Province, White Knights of Liberty.
    - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Transcript pdf (Digital-materials RL11363-SET-0002, Object RL11363-PDF-0027.PDF)
  - Mary Sutes, Yadkin County, NC, 1984-08-04; 8 pages
    Queen Kleagle, White Knights of Liberty, Knights of the KKK.
    - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Transcript pdf (Digital-materials RL11363-SET-0002, Object RL11363-PDF-0028.PDF)
  - Sue Thomas, Tuscumbia, AL, 1984-07-20; 9 pages
    Klanslady, Knights of the KKK.
    - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Transcript pdf (Digital-materials RL11363-SET-0002, Object RL11363-PDF-0029.PDF)
  - Jim Warner, Irvine, CA, 1987-10-10; 01:11:36
    Founding member, American Nazi Party; Grand Dragon, Knights of the Ku Klux Klan. Interview conducted at 8th Annual Institute for Historical Review (IHR) Conference
    - Original audiocassette, sides 1 and 2 (Box 4, Audio-cassette RL11363-CS-0038)
    - Digital audio file, part 1 (Digital-materials RL11363-SET-0001, Object RL11363-CS-0038_01.WAV)
    - Digital audio file, part 2 (Digital-materials RL11363-SET-0001, Object RL11363-CS-0038_02.WAV)
  - Lyn Wells with Janet Caldwell, Atlanta, GA, 1985-07-17; 00:46:04
    Anti-Klan Network activists
    - Original audiocassette, sides 1 (partial) and 2 (Box 3, Audio-cassette RL11363-CS-0010)
    - Digital audio file, part 1 (interview begins at 00:30:57). (Digital-materials RL11363-SET-0001, Object RL11363-CS-0010_01.WAV)
    - Digital audio file, part 2 (Digital-materials RL11363-SET-0001, Object RL11363-CS-0010_02.WAV)
  - Bill Wilkinson, 1980-10; 00:55:56
    Imperial Wizard Invisible Empire KKK.
    - Original audiocassette, sides 1 and 2 (Box 3, Audio-cassette RL11363-CS-0034)
    - Digital audio file, part 1 (Digital-materials RL11363-SET-0001, Object RL11363-CS-0034_01.WAV)
    - Digital audio file, part 2 (Digital-materials RL11363-SET-0001, Object RL11363-CS-0034_02.WAV)
- Correspondence and Name Files, 2
  - Black, Don: Notes from a non-taped conversation, 1985 Mar. 24 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Black, Don: correspondence, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Bridges, Tyler: correspondence, 1990 and undated (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Center for Democratic Renewal; Dees, Morris, 1985, 1990 and undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
    Photocopies of Morris Dees (SPLC) mail and conversation transcript with Berryhills, and a letter from the Center for Democratic Renewal.
  - Duke, David: poetry and photographs, 1985-1989 and undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
    Handwritten poetry, KKK doodles, and drafts of notes by Duke for Evelyn Rich, written on notebook paper and La Quinta Hotel stationary. Also, assorted photographs of Duke, including at Populist Party meeting.
  - Johnson, Ronald, and Bob Hoy, John Nugent, William Pierce: contact information, undated (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Kennedy, Stetson: correspondence, 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Warner, James (Jim): Notes (incomplete), undated (Box 1, Folder 37)
    2 copies.
- Far Right Groups, 3
  - Notes, Printed Material, Ephemera
    - Rich's dissertation: "Ku Klux Klan Ideology 1954-1988" (Box 1, Folder 38)
      Boston University.
    - Citizens' Council newspaper, Jackson, MS, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 39)
      Vol. 1, number 6
    - Sons of Liberty ephemera, 1980s (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Mikell, Robert: "They say-blood on my hands; the story of Robert M. Shelton, Imperial Wizard of the United Klans of America", 1966 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Ku Klux Klan: White Patriot newspaper, Tuscumbia, AL, 1982-1986; 2 folders (Box 1, Folder 42-43)
      Scattered issues.
    - Stewart, John L.: "KKK Menace: The cross against people", 1980 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Beam, Louis: "Essays of a Klansman," AKIA Publications, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Ku Klux Klan: White Patriot newspaper, Metairie, LA, 1980s (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Ku Klux Klan: The Crusader newspaper, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Knights of the Ku Klux Klan: The Klansman newspaper, 1976-1985 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Knights of the Ku Klux Klan ephemera, 1980s (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Invisible Empire, Knights of the Ku Klux Klan ephemera and pamphlets, 1980s (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Invisible Empire, Knights of the Ku Klux Klan: Negatives from Bill Wilkerson (probably) rally, Connecticut, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Ku Klux Klan (assorted) ephemera, flyers, 1980s (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Ku Klux Klan (assorted) photographs of rallies, in Georgia and unknown, 1985 and undated (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Ku Klux Klan notes from rally, Raleigh, NC, 1985 Feb. 24 (Box 2, Folder 54)
      Including quotes by Glenn Miller. Recording CS-0031.
    - AKIA: Inter-Klan Newsletter and Survival Alert, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Ku Klux Klan: loose photographs of Klansmen, undated (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Populist Party: The Populist Observer newspaper, 1989-1992 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Populist Party: National Committee Meeting agenda, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Populist Party pamphlets, 1984-1988 and undated (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - National Alliance: Report of visit by Rich and David Duke to headquarters, 1985 Apr. 19-20; 10 pages (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - White Patriot Party: The Confederate Leader newspaper, 1984-1986 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - White Patriot Party: Transcript of rally, Jasper, GA, 1985 Jul. 13; 7 pages (Box 2, Folder 62)
      Recording CS-0022, CS-0010.
    - White Patriot Party: Transcript of rally, Kennesaw, GA, 1985 Aug. 3 (Box 2, Folder 63)
      3 copies. Recording CS-0029.
    - White Patriot Party: photographs and negatives of rallies, undated; 2 folders (Box 2, Folder 64-65)
      Presumably from Jasper and Kennesaw, GA.
    - New Christian Crusade Church: Christian Vanguard newspaper, 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - New Christian Crusade Church: The CDL Report, Arabi and Metairie, LA, 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 67)